Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory9 Mss.B.B61.inventory09
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents M
  - Moley, Raymond C. (Box 64)
    - R. C. Moley -- to H.L. Ickes, 1933 Mar. 24; 1p
    - (Enc. with Moley, R.C., Mar. 24, 1933)
  - Molina, Enriquez M. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1910 Sept. 12; 1p.
  - Mollison, Theodor (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Jan. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 1; 1p.
  - Mommsen, Adelheid (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1933 May 13; 2p.
  - Mond, Robert L. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 15; 2p.
    - See Waldman, M.B., July 19, 1937
    - Robert Mond -- from Anon., 1937 Mar. 5
  - Monroe, Paul (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1917 Aug. 7
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Aug. 20
    - Paul Monroe -- to Elizabeth Watson, 1931 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - (Enc: originally with letter from Lucy A. Branham, Jan. 19, 1932)
  - Montague, William P. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 May 15; 1p.
  - Montesinos, Jose (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1937 Sept. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 23; 1p.
  - Montgomery, James A. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 6; 1p.
  - Montor, M. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1923 Apr. 1; 1p.
  - Moody, Paul D. (Box 64)
    - Paul D. Moody -- to C.T. McAvoy, 1938 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - (Enc: with McAvoy, C.T. to Efron, D., Jan. 31, 1938)
  - Moody, William (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1899 Jan. 5; 1p.
  - Moon, Chas.(?) (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1906 Sept. 24
  - Moon, Parker T. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1926 Sept. 21; 1p.
  - Mooney, James (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1905 Mar. 15
    - From Boas, 1906 Sept. 19
    - From Boas, 1919 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Sept. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1888 Nov. 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1896 Jan. 11
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov. 21
    - To Boas, 1896 Dec. 10
    - To Boas, 1898 June 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 10
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 27
    - To Boas, 1906 Sept.8
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 5; 1p.
    - James Mooney -- to J.P. Dunn, 1907 Sept. 25
    - James Mooney -- to J.P. Dunn, 1907 Oct. 2
    - James Mooney -- from J.P. Dunn, 1907 Oct. 19
    - James Mooney -- to U.S. Dept of Justice, 1917 Nov. 1
  - Moore, Chauncey O. (Mrs.) (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1936 June 20; 1p.
  - Moore, Clarence B. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1903 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1908 May 23
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 6
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 2
    - To Boas, 1908 May 25
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 16
  - Moore, Fred Atkins (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 5; 1p.
  - Moore, George F. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 4; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1922 Nov. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 29; 1p.
  - Moore, Harriet (Box 64)
    - Harriet Moore -- from Lydia Nadejena, 1942 Apr. 17
  - Moore, Harry E. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 31; 1p.
  - Moore, Harry L. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 21
  - Moore, John Bassett (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1919 Aug. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 May 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Aug. 20 and 30
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 11
    - To Boas, 1919 Aug. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 2; 1p.
    - (Enc: Letter to Jobling, James from J.B. Moore dated April 2, 1920), 1920 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Oct. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - J.B. Moore -- to James W. Jobling, 1920 Apr. 2; 1p.
  - Moore, John G. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 17; 2p.
  - Moore, J. Jay (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 17
  - Moore, J.F. (Mrs.) (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1899 Jan. 6; 1p.
  - Moore, J. Stanley (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 18; 1p.
  - Moore, L. B. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 20
  - Moore, Mildred Downs (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1939 July 16; 2p.
  - Moore, Richard B. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 8; 1p.
  - Moore, Robert F. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 2; 1p.
  - Moore, R. G. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 May 3; 1p.
  - Moore's W.B., Newspaper Subsc. Ser. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1898 Dec. 29
  - Moore's W.H., Newspaper Subsc. Agency (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1898 Oct.
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 26
  - Moore-Cottrell Subsc. Agencies (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 9; 1p.
  - Moorehead, Warren King (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 12
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 3
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 9
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 28
    - To Boas, 1914 Sept. 13
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 9
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Sept. 20; 1p.
    - (Enc: Handbook of the American Indians; Suggestions for republications), 1935 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - (Enc: Wissler, C. to Moorehead, W.K., and Moorehead, W.K. to McClure, B., Oct. 10, 1935 Oct. 14, 1935)
    - W.K. Moorehead -- to B. McClure, 1935 Oct. 14; 2p.
    - W.K. Moorehead -- from C. Wissler, 1935 Oct. 10
    - (Enc. with Moorehead, W.K., Oct. 15, 1935)
  - Moorehouse, G. M. (Box 64)
    - See Gregory, W.K., Jan. 8,1931
  - Moorhouse, G. W. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1892 Dec. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1894 July 26
    - To Boas, 1894 Aug. 6
    - To Boas, 1894 July 28
  - Moosdorf, Wilhelm (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1923 Sept. 1; 1p.
  - More, Paul (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 8
  - Moreau, Albert (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 7; 1p.
  - Morecroft, John (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1925 July 18; 1p.
  - Morehouse, T. C. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1936 July 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 May 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 June 20; 1p.
  - Morey, Charles R. (Box 64)
    - To Boas (open letter), 1p.
    - (Enc: with Nadejena, Lydia, Mar. 25, 1942)
  - Morf, Heinrich (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1913 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1914 May 19
    - From Boas, 1915 Apr. 24
    - To Boas, 1913 Aug. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Sept. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1915 Sept. 1; 1p.
  - Morgan, Agnes B. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 26
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 11
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 24
  - Morgan, B. Q. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 11; 1p.
  - Morgan, C. M. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1933 (end); 2p.
  - Morgan, Edith (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 23; 1p.
  - Morgan, Edwin (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1923 May 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Apr. 11; 1p.
  - Morgan, Frank H. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 23
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 21
  - Morgan, J. Pierpont (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1907 May 17
  - Morgan, O. S. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 15; 1p.
  - Morgan, T[homas] H[unt] (?) (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1927 July 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 May 23
    - (see Boas, F. to Wheeler, W.M., May 23, 1933), 1935 May 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 June 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 24; 1p.
    - T. H. Morgan -- from P. Brockett, 1931 Mar. 12
  - Morgan, William H. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1915 Dec. 11
  - Morganstern, Ruth (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 6; 1p.
  - Morgenthau, Henry (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 May 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Oct. 26; 1p.
  - Morice, A[drien] G[abriel] (?) (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 11
    - From Boas, 1924 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1924 Feb. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Aug. 6
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 31
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 21
    - To Boas, 1924 Feb. 7; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 31; 1p. (?)
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas (receipt), 1931 Feb. 13
  - Moriceaws, A. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1917 May 18
  - Morison, O. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1888 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1889 Apr. 22; 1p.
  - Morley, R. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1911 June 3; 2p.
  - Morrell, Murray (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1940 Sept. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Sept. 23; 1p.
  - Morrey, James (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1898 June 10
  - Morris, Alice V. (Mrs. D.H.) (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 June 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 6; 1p.
  - Morris, Charles S. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 1
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 6
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 8
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 17
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 19
    - To Boas, 1907 Sept. 13
  - Morris, C. V. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1927 July 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 July 9; 1p.
  - Morris, Dave H. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 6; 1p.
  - Morris, Earl (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 22; 1p.
      (open letter)
      Re Dr. A. A. Goldenweiser
    - (Enc. originally with Barnes, H.E., July 8, 1918), 1928 July 30; 1p.
  - Morris, Edmund (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1909 Mar. 30
  - Morris, Ernest (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1927 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 4; 1p.
  - Morris, Newbold (Box 64)
    - See Dearborn, N.H., Sept. 24, 1938
  - Morris, Richard S. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1941 Apr. 24; 1p.
  - Morris, Samuel B. (Box 64)
    - Samuel B. Morris -- to Clyde R. Miller, 1939 July 7; 1p.
  - Morris, William, Jr. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 4; 1p.
  - Morrison, J. Clarke (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1927 May 28; 5p.
  - Morrow, Mrs. D.W. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 17; 1p.
  - Morrow, Harold M. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1931 May 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 May 4; 1p.
  - Morrow, L.W.W. (Box 64)
    - See Davies, C.E., Feb.5, 1931
  - Morsbach (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 4; 4p.
  - Morschowski, M. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1935 May 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 27; 3p.
  - Morse, E. L. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1889 Oct. 30; 1p.
  - Morse, Edward Sylvester (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1906 Sept. 24
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 22
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 27
    - To Boas, 1899 June 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 29
  - Morse, Fannie French (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 19; 1p.
  - Morse, James R. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1904 Feb. 18; 1p.
  - Morse, Josiah (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1913 Mar. 10
    - To Boas, 1913 Feb. 24
  - Morse, Marston (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1941 Nov. 7; 1p.
  - Morse, S.(?) (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1887 Jan. 10
  - Morse, S. H. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1941 July 31; 1p.
  - Morton, Dudley J. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1930 Jan. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 8; 1p.
  - Morton, Florence (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1927 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Aug. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Aug. 29; 1p.
  - Morton, F. S. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1909 Oct. 23
  - Morwitz, Ernst (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 7; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Sept. 29; 1p.
  - Moscholke, E. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 8; 1p.
  - Moscow State University (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 11; 1p.
  - Moscowitz & Rosenthal (Box 64)
    - Moscowitz & Rosenthal -- to American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom, 1939 May 25; 2p.
  - Moser, E. S. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 23; 1p.
  - Mosher, J. S. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1937 Dec. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 9; 1p.
  - Mosher, W. E. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 4; 1p.
  - Moskowitz, Henry (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1936 Sept. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - See Field, F., Sept. 20, 1935
  - Moss, C. R. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1921 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Nov. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Dec. 28; 1p.
  - Moss, F. A. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 27; 1p.
  - Moss, Leslie B. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 25; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 18; 1p.
  - Moss, Maude (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 June 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 June 23; 1p.
  - Mosse, Rudolf (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1885 May 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1886 June 16; 1p.
  - Mossman, Dorothy (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1935 May 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 7; 1p.
  - Mosthaff, E. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1885 June 16
    - To Boas, 1885 June 24
    - To Boas, 1885 July 28
  - Motherwell, Hiram (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 7; 1p.
  - Motor Habits in the Lives of Various Nationalities (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 8; 3p.
  - Mott, Lewis F. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 5; 1p.
  - Mott Haven Health District (Box 64)
    - See Pessar, H.T.-, 2-14-36, 2-17 4-29-36, 5-14-36, 6-1-36
  - Moulton, Forest Ray (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Sept. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Nov. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 23; 1p.
  - Moulton, Harold G. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1928 Jan. 18; 1p.
  - Mousseau, Marie (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept. 7; 1p.
  - Movie (Box 64)
    See Gestures
  - Moylan, G. L. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 12; 1p.
  - Mü? (Mücheler, P.?) (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 12; 1p.
  - Mu Alpha Nu (Box 64)
    See McNary, Martha
  - Mücheler,, P.? (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1925 Mar. 6; 3p.
  - Mudge, Isadore Gilbert (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Nov. 21
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 14; 1p.
  - Mueller, A. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1932 Feb. 29; 1p.
  - Mueller, C. B. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 28; 1p.
  - Mueller, Friederich von (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 12; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 13; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 16; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 18; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 June 30; 2p
  - Mueller, G. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 5; 1p.
  - Mueller, H. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 28; 2p.
  - Mueller, Heinrich von (Box 64)
    - (open letter), 1930 Sept. 26; 1p.
    - Heinrich von Mueller -- to Senatoren, 1930 Sept. 26; 1p.
    - Heinrich von Mueller -- to Senatoren, 1931 Jan. 2; 1p.
  - Mueller, Herbert (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept. 14; 2p.
  - Mueller, J. A. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 28; 1p.
  - Mueller, Karl Alexander von (Box 64)
    - See Seeliger, H., Feb. 20, 1922
    - K.A. v. Mueller -- to Senatoren, 1933 Aug. 19; 1p.
  - Mueller, Margarethe (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 19; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 31; 2p.
    - Margaretha Mueller -- from Mary Caswell, 1906 Feb. 19
    - Margaretha Mueller -- from Mary Caswell, 1906 Feb. 20
  - Mueller, Max (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - (see Meyer, J.P., Mar. 27, 1923)
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 13; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 21; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 29; 1p.
  - Mueller, Walter (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1939 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1942 Dec. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 16; 1p.
    - (Enc: What Is At Stake? 2p.), 1939 Dec. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas (open letter), 1940 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 June 16; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Nov. 15; 3p.
    - Walter Mueller -- from Miles M. Goldberg, 1940 Apr. 19
    - Walter Mueller -- to J.E. Lips, 1939 Dec. 13; 1p.
      Also see Munich
  - Mueller, W.M. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 27
  - Muenchen, Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 6; 1p.
  - Muenchen, Deutsche Akademie (Box 64)
    See Mueller, Karl Alexander von
    - To Boas, 1933 July 8; 1p.
  - Muenchen Universitat Anthropologisches Institut (Box 64)
    See Martin, Rud.
  - Muensterberg, Hugo (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1903 Nov. 6
    - From Boas, 1905 Apr. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1910 Feb. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1910 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Oct. 28; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Apr. 2; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Apr. 8; 7p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 15; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1910 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - Muensterberger, W. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1935 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 15; 1p.
  - Muetzel, Gustav (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1886 Apr. 12
  - Mullan, Mrs. G.V. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1903 Nov. 27; 1p.
  - Muller, E. G. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1935 July 7; 1p.
  - Mumford, D. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1924 Jan. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 16; 1p.
  - Mumford, Louis (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1939 Sept. 17; 1p.
  - Munich -- (also see "Muenchen") (Box 64)
    - Report of a meeting, 1929 June 6; 4p.
  - Munro, D. A. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1909 Mar. 8
  - Munro, W.B. (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 13
    - (see Tyler, H.W., Feb. 13,1931)
  - Murchison, Carl (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1928 Sept. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 6; 1p.
  - Murdoch, George P. (Box 64)
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 23; 1p.
  - Murdoch, John (Box 64)
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec. 3
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec. 13
    - To Boas, 1888 Jan. 4
    - To Boas, 1888 Jan. 27
    - To Boas, 1889 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1896 May 25
    - To Boas, 1896 June 8
    - To Boas, 1896 July 12
    - To Boas, 1896 July 21
    - To Boas, 1896 Aug. 21
  - Murphy, Barbara (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 10; 1p.
  - Murphy, Gardner (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 July 10; 1p.
    - (Enc: Murphy, Gardner to Lehman, H.H., July 10, 1936), 1937 Nov. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies, 1938 Jan.
    - To Boas, 1938 June 13; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept. 21 and Sept. 28; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. Paper on modern population., 1939 July
    - To Boas, 1939 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - Gardner Murphy -- to J.C. Bobbright, 1929 Oct. 16; 1p.
      (Enc: Likert, R.A. study of factors determining public opinion.)
    - Gardner Murphy -- to Lehman, H.H., 1936 July 10; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Murphy, Gardner, July 10, 1936)
  - Murphy, Mrs. Gardner (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 20; 1p.
  - Murphy, Henry R. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 15; 1p.
  - Murphy, Roy D. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1941 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - Roy D. Murphy -- to P. Joseph, 1941 Feb. 17; 1p.
  - Murphy, Starr (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1906 Nov. 23
  - Murphy, T. F. (Box 65)
    - T. F. Murphy -- to Werner Grunwald, 1941 end; 1p.
  - Murray, Gilbert (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 15; 2p.
    - Gilbert Murray -- to Shotwell, 1933 May 13; 4p.
  - Murray, Thomas C. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 26; 1p.
  - Murride, Mayfair M. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1908 Feb. 6
  - Murrill, W.A. (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1907 Aug. 30
  - Murrow, E. R. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Sept. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Sept. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Sept. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 June 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 July 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 3; 1p.
    - (Enc: List of dismissed German scholars), 1934 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Sept. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Sept. 18; 1p.
    - (Enc: Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars. Statement of Assets and Liabilities, Sept. 17, 1934), 1934 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 June 3; 1p.
    - E.R. Murrow -- L.C. Dunn, 1934 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - E.R. Murrow -- to Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars. Executive Committee., 1934 Sept. 24; 1p.
    - (Enc: Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars. Minutes, Sept. 18, 1934.)
    - E.R. Murrow -- to F.D. Fackenthal, 1935 Apr. 9; 1p.
    - (Enc: Fackenthal, F.D. to Murrow, E.R., Apr. 10, 1935)
    - E.R. Murrow -- from F.D. Fackenthal, 1935 Apr. 10
    - (Enc: with Murrow, E.R. to Fackenthal, F.D., Apr. 9, 1935)
    - E.R. Murrow -- to F.D. Fackenthal, 1935 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - E.R. Murrow -- to F.D. Fackenthal, 1935 June 14; 1p.
    - E.R. Murrow -- to E.R.A. Seligman, 1935 June 5
    - (Enc: with Seligman, E.R.A., June 5, 1935)
  - Mursell, George R. (Box 65)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 2; 1p.
  - Museum of American Indian (Box 65)
    See Clemens, James B.
    - James Paytiamo -- to Museum of American Indian, 1930 July 14
  - Museum für Volkerkunde, Berlin (Box 65)
    - To Boas, 1886 Dec. 3; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1895 Aug. 10; 1p.